Meier mss., 1927-2010
Indiana University Digital Library Program
Meier mss.
1927-2010
Lilly Library (Indiana University, Bloomington) Indiana University 1200 E. Seventh St. Bloomington, IN 47405-5500 Phone: 812-855-2452 Fax: 812-855-3143 Email: liblilly@indiana.edu http://www.indiana.edu/~liblilly
Meier, Deborah
LMC 2653
ca. 7,650 items
The Meier mss., 1927-2010, consists of the correspondence and papers of education reformer Deborah W. Meier (1931-), who is frequently credited with founding the modern small schools movement in the United States.
Access Restrictions
Some files are closed to researchers.
Biographical Note
Deborah Meier was born on April 6, 1931 in New York City and received a master’s degree in history from the University of Chicago in 1955. She began her career in education in 1963 as a kindergarten teacher in Chicago. In 1966, she returned to New York City, where she taught at PS 144 and was involved in open-corridor class experiments. In 1974, Meier started Central Park East, which was later expanded into three schools: Central Park East I, Central Park East II, and River East. In 1985, Meier and the Central Park East staff again expanded the school, this time adding Central Park East Secondary School for students in 7th through 12th grade. Her work at Central Park East brought her recognition in the form of a MacArthur fellowship, which she received in 1987. From 1992 to 1996, Meier also served as co-director of the Coalition Campus Schools Project, an initiative to restructure large, failing high schools into multiple smaller schools. In 1997, Meier left New York City to found Mission Hill, a pilot elementary school in Boston, where she served as principal until 2005. Meier has written numerous articles and several books on education, including The Power of Their Ideas: Lessons for America from a Small School in Harlem. She has received much recognition for her work, including honorary degrees from Harvard, Yale, Brown, and other universities.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into the following series: I. Biographical; II. Education; III. Correspondence; IV. Writings and speeches; V. Writings by others; VI. Professional activities; VII. Honors and awards; VIII. Politics; IX. Recordings and multimedia; X. Additions.
Scope and Content Note
The Meier mss., 1927-2009, consists of the papers of Deborah Willen Meier (1931-), an education reformer and the founder of the modern small schools movement in the United States. Materials in the collection include schoolwork and childhood writings by Meier; personal, political, and professional correspondence; drafts and final copies of many of Meier’s writings; writings by others on Meier and her projects; notes for speeches; documents on the organization of the Central Park East schools, Mission Hill school, the Coalition Campus Schools Project, and other educational initiatives; school newsletters and mailings to parents; student work and recorded performances; student assessments; conference materials; honors and awards; and video and audio recordings of Meier interviews and speeches.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in IUCAT, the IU Libraries' online catalog. Materials about related topics, persons or places can be found by searching the catalog using these terms.
Names
Meier, Deborah
Sizer, Theodore R.
Willen, Joseph
Willen, Pearl L.
Central Park East Elementary School (New York, N.Y.)
Central Park East Secondary School (New York, N.Y.)
Mission Hill School (Boston, M.A.)
Coalition Campus Schools Project (New York, N.Y.)
New York Networks for School Renewal (New York, N.Y.)
Topics
Educational innovations --United States.
Educators --United States.
School management and organization --United States.
Small schools --United States.
Teaching --United States.
Related Material
Many of Deborah Meier's writings can also be found on her web page: http://www.deborahmeier.com
Administrative Information
Acquisition Information
Acquired: 2009, 2010
- Biographical, 1929-1995, undated (Box 1)
  - Professional, 1972-1994, undated (Box 1)
    - Biographical sketches and lists of writings, 1980-1994, undated
    - Resumes and employment records, 1972-1983, undated
  - Personal, 1929-1995, undated (Box 1)
    - Address book, 1944
    - Drawings, undated
    - Journal fragments, undated
    - Camp newsletter, 1947
    - Memorabilia from trips to Europe, 1945-1949
    - Clippings on Meier, family, and friends, 1941-1964, undated
    - Clippings on Meier, family, and friends, 1941-1964, undated (Box 3)
    - Willen family papers and writings, 1929-1963, undated (Box 1)
    - Goldie Larner schoolwork, undated
    - Fred Meier contract, business cards, 1955, undated
    - Becky Meier (daughter) baby schedule, art, 1956-1959
    - Story by Sarah Meier-Zimbler (granddaughter), 1995
    - Financial papers, 1987-2004, undated
    - 60th birthday party, 1991
      - Party planning and family tree, 1991
      - RSVPs, 1991
      - Memory book, 1991
      - Birthday cards, 1991
    - 70th birthday party invitation, 2001
- Education, 1931-1999, undated (Box 1)
  - Ethical Culture Fieldston School and childhood, 1931-1999, undated (Box 1)
    - Schoolwork and writings, 1936-1949, undated
      - 1936-1941
      - 1942-1943
      - 1943-1944
      - 1944-1945
      - 1945-1946
      - 1946-1947
      - 1947-1948
      - 1948-1949
      - Undated, (2 folders)
      - Unidentified work and work by others, 1943, undated
    - School activities and newsletters, 1943-1944, undated
    - Lists and sign-up sheets, 1943-1949, undated
    - Assessments and report cards, 1931-1943
    - Reunion programs, 1959-1999
      - 1959
      - 1989
      - 1999
  - Antioch College, 1949-1951, undated (Box 1)
    - Application essays and acceptance letters, 1949
    - Academic and social activities, 1950-1951
    - Co-op program, 1949-1951
      - Report on Harrisburg Evening News, 1949
      - Journals from Indianapolis Day Nursery, 1950
      - United States Senate Chamber passes, 1951
    - Achievement exam grades, 1950
    - Miscellaneous writings, 1949-1950, undated
  - University of Chicago, 1950-1955, undated (Box 1)
    - Application essay, ca. 1951
    - Coursework, 1950-1955, undated
      - 1950-1952
      - 1953-1955
      - Undated
    - Diploma, 1955
  - Post-graduate, 1963-1999 (Box 1)
    - Transcripts, 1967-1999
    - Outward Bound course, 1992
- Correspondence, 1927-2009, undated (Box 1)
  - Personal, 1927-2006, undated (Box 1)
    - Letters to Meier, 1942-2006, undated
      Arranged chronologically
      This is a partial list of correspondents with approximate dates of letters from each correspondent:
      Abel, Sonia and Paul Abel, 1995
      Abramovic, Emil, 1947-1948
      Abrams, Irwin, 1951
      Abrams, Ruth (Mrs. Albert B. Abrams), 1956
      Adams, Evelyne (Evey), 1949
      Aher, Gertrude and Jim, 1952
      Antioch College, 1949-1951
      Apelman, Maja, 1991, 1995-1996, general 1990-2009
      Asker, Betsy, 1947
      Babis, Sally, 1949
      Baker, Carol, 1951
      Bayes, Ellie, 1946
      Bentley, A. Jane, 1950
      Berlin, Susan, 1991
      Bernstein, Bonnie, 1946-1947
      Berry, Jim, 1952
      Block, Arthur S., 1968
      B'Nai B'Rith, 1949
      Bolitzer, Bernie, 1961
      Brandon, Sue, 1946-1947
      Brickner, Phil, 1947-1949
      Brown, D. S., 1950
      Brown, Joyce, 1992-1995, 1998, 2003
      Calder, Nigel D. R., 1949-1950
      Callenbach, Chick, 1954
      Carmichael, Lucianne, 1991 1995, 2002
      Cohen, Marshall, 1946
      Cohen, Rita (Rita Bird), 1949-1951
      Cohn, Goldye (Mrs. Herman Cohn), 1951
      Corey, Lewis, 1951
      Cruzen, Marianne (Skipper), 1950-1951
      Dames, Lucy and Joe, 1950-1951
      Davidon, Bill, 1964
      Democratic Socialists of America, general 1990-2009
      Dombrow, Ruth, Max, and Susan, 1964
      Dreitzer, Judy, 1944
      Dufault, Ruth, 1996
      East River Savings Bank, 1951
      Elgin, Mrs., 1950
      Fabian Society, 1949
      Fagen, David, 1951
      Federation of Jewish Philanthropies of New York, 1950-1951
      Fetter, Neil, 1949
      Fieldston School, 1949
      Fieldston Social Committee, 1944
      Fierman[?], Karl (Cubby), 1944
      Fischer, G., 1944
      Fischer, Louis, 1948
      Fitzgerald, Mike, 1949
      Flanders, Tamzen and Karl Kirchwey, 1992
      Frohlich, Sue, 1950
      Garrison, Lloyd, 1948-1950
      Gates, Albert, 1950
      Gethman, Margaret (Mag, Maggie), 1951-1954, 1956
      Gibbon, Janet, 2003, 2005
      Gold[???], Sean, 1948-1949
      Goldsmith, Richard, 1951
      Good, Elizabeth (Meier's daughter-in-law), 1993-1994, 2005
      Greenberg, Rabbi Simon, 1949
      Greenwald, Babs, 1946
      Greenwald, Susan, 1944
      H., Barbara, 1944
      H., J. William (Bill), 1950-1951
      Handorff, Joel, 1997
      Harris, Don, 1952
      Harrisburg Newspaper Guild, 1950
      Herling, Alice D., 1994
      Heymann, Frederick G., 1952
      Higley, L. Wayne, 1951-1954, 1987-1988
      See also: Oversize 1
      Hochheimer, Alice, 1942, 1944-1947
      Hollander, Judy, 1954
      Hunt, Carolyn, general 1990-2009
      Jaffe, Natalie, 1951
      Kabach, Anne, 1994
      Kato, Hiroki, 1964
      Katz, Robert D. (Bob), 1947
      Kaufman, Faith Evelyn (Cookie), 1946
      Kirsch, Judith D., 1993
      Klesmer, Louise R., 1949-1951, 1956
      Knox, Robert M. (Bob), 1950-1951
      Kook, Patricia (Patsy, Pat, Stubbs, Stubby, Kookie, Patricia Gibbs, Mrs. Bud H. Gibbs), 1943-1951, 1953, 1956
      Kris, Anna, 1944-1945, 1949-1954, 1956
      Kronsky, Betty Jane, 1944
      Kuehne, Carla T., 1943-1944
      Lacovara, Madeline, 1994
      Lane, Nancy (Nan), 1949-1950
      Larner, Babe (Meier's aunt), 1951, 1956
      Larner, Clara (Mrs. Martin L. Larner), 1950-1951
      Larner, Donald (Don), 1995-1996
      Larner, (Mrs.?) Irvin M., 1944
      Larner, Judy, 1956
      Larner, Margie, 1965
      Larner, Martin L. (Marty), 1994, 1949-1950, 1952
      Larner, Sarah (Mrs. Mayer Larner, grandma; Meier's grandmother), 1946, 1948-1952, 1954-1958
      Larner, Sara, 1949, 1956
      Larner, Victor (Meier's uncle), 1943, 1949-1950, 1953-1954
      League for Industrial Democracy, 1952
      Leed, Richard (Dick), 1949-1951
      Lenrow, Elbert, 1948
      Leuba, Richard J. (Dick), 1950
      Levin, Adrienne, 2003
      Lewis, Sally, 1946
      Lieber, [???], 1994
      Litt, Bobby, 1944, 1946-1947, 1949-1950
      Litt, Pauline, 1949
      Lowenstein, Florence I., 1949, 1965
      Lowenstein, Dorothy (Dot, ., Dotty, Dottie, Mrs. Andre B. Van Hoogen), 1944-1952, 1954, 1964-1965
      Macmahon, Gail, 1949
      Maher, Jane (Janie, Jane Willen, Jane Mills; Meier's sister-in-law), 1950-1954 1956-1958, 1962, 1993, 1996
      Martin, Marla (Marla Arkow), 1995
      Martin, Ralph and Marge, 1949
      Martus, Marjorie (Marge), 1992
      McDonald, Lorraine
      McDonald, Shirley, 1949
      McGinnis, Cora, 1949-1950
      McIntosh, Millicent, 1993
      Meier, Daniel and Lilli Meier (Meier's grandchildren), general 1990-2009
      Meier, Frederic C. (Fred, F.; Meier's husband), 1954, 1956
      Meier, Nicholas (Nick; Meier's son), 1997
      Meier, Rebecca (Becky; Meier's daughter), 1995, 2002
      Meier, Roger (Meier's son), 1988
      Meier, Vivian (Meier's mother-in-law), 1952-1953, 1956
      Meier-Zimbler, Ezra Milton (Meier's grandson), 1995-1996
      Meier-Zimbler, Sarah Pearl (Meier's granddaughter), 1994, 1996, 2006
      Messner, Berti (Bert, Bertie), 1949-1952, 1954
      Mills, Andrew S. (A., A. S., Andy), 1953-1957, 1962
      Mintz, Marjorie G.(Marge, Margie), ca. 1943-1944, 1947-1948
      Morrison, Dr. Donald A. R., 1957
      Mott, Anne (Annie), 1944-1949, 1951-1952, 1954
      Mt. Neboh Congregation, 1943
      N., Fred, 1950
      Nachman, Louise, 1947
      New School for Social Research, 1949
      Oppenheimer, Adeline (Addy), 1944
      Partridge, D., 1944
      Pasternak, Blanche, 1944
      Pester, Rhea, 1949-1951
      Pioneer Youth of America, 1942
      Poindexter, Anne(Annie), 1950
      R., Bobby, 1946
      R., Jeannine, 1943-1944
      Radetsky, Charles, 1954
      Rahn, Mary Lee
      Riordan, Anita (Ynety), 1942, 1946
      Rogers, Doris, 1946-1947, 1949-1950
      Rosenblum, Bea, 1946, 1948
      Rosenstock, Larry, 1996
      Rosenzwhig[?], Joyce, 1944
      Rotondi, B., 1964
      Russel, Myra T., 1995, 1997-1998, 2000, 2003
      Russell, Ed and Sarah Russell, 1951
      Russell, Esther A., 1954
      S., E. J. (Bettie), 1950
      Sager, Norma Carol, 1944
      Salwitz, Janet (Jan), 1947
      Samuel, Ralph E., 1951
      Saxton, John H., 1950
      Schantz, Penny, 1993, general 1990-2009
      Schaupp, M., 1954
      Schiller, Robert H. (Bob), 1951
      Schroeder, Marilyn, 1949
      Schulte family, 1954
      Schwartz, Anne, 1947
      Sears, Jayne, 1950
      Shortall, Nora, 1949
      Silberman, Arlene, 1994-1996
      Siegel, Gloria, 1944
      Sievers, Mrs. Maurice J., 1949
      Simon, R. (Bob), 1950
      Sinclair, Barbara, 1954
      Slawson, John, 1949
      St. Clair, Barbara Abels, 1995
      St. Louis Post-Dispatch, 1950
      Stein, Leslie, general 1990-2009
      Steinfels, Peggy and Peter, 1995
      Sultan, Edith Joan, 1944
      Sunshine, Tillie, 1947
      Taberski, Paul (Pablo), 1950
      Takacs, Dorothea (Takie, Tak), 1949-1952
      Thompson, Ben (Benjie), 1994
      Toepfer, 1949
      Truesdell, W. E., 1954
      United States Playing Card Company, 1943
      Van Hoogen, Andre, 1962
      Venezia, Nilly, 1993-1995
      Weinstein, Leonard, M.D., 1957
      Wells, Katherine (Mrs. Henry W. Wells), 1952
      Wersba, Lois, 1943, 1946-1947
      White, Cheryl Stitham (Cherie, Cher), 2003
      Willen, Drenka (Drenka Palic; Meier's sister-in-law), 1956
      Willen, Joseph (Joe, Dad, Pop; Meier's father), 1943-1944, 1946, 1948-1957
      Willen, Paul L. (Meier's brother), 1943, 1945-1957, 1993, 1995
      Willen, Pearl L. (Mom, Mama; Meier's mother), 1943-1946, 1948-1958, 1964-1965
      Willen, Samuel, 1943
      Wilson, Nancy, 1955-1956
      Wohl, R. Richard, 1954
      Wolff, Anna, 1964
      Wolff, Viola, 1943
      Wood, Hilary, 1944
      The Wyverns, 1954
      Zabin, Ann Dorothy, 1944
      - 1942
      - 1943, Jan.-July
      - 1943, Aug.-Dec.,general 1943
      - 1944, Jan.-July (Box 2)
      - 1944, Aug.
      - 1944, Sept.-Dec.,general 1944
      - 1945
      - 1946, Jan.-July 15
      - 1946, July 16-31
      - 1946, Aug.
      - 1946, Aug. (Box 3)
      - 1946, Sept.-Dec.,general 1946 (Box 2)
      - 1947, Jan.-Sept.
      - 1947, Oct.-Dec.,general 1947
      - 1948, Jan.-June
      - 1948, July-Dec.
      - General 1948
      - General 1948 (Box 3)
      - 1949, Jan.-Apr. (Box 2)
      - 1949, May-June
      - 1949, July
      - 1949, Aug.
      - 1949, Sept.-Oct
      - 1949, Nov.
      - 1949, Dec. 1-11
      - 1949, Dec. 12-31
      - General 1949
      - 1950, Jan.
      - 1950, Feb.
      - 1950, Mar.
      - 1950, Apr.
      - 1950, May
      - 1950, June
      - 1950, July-Aug.
      - 1950, Sept.
      - 1950, Sept. (Box 3)
      - 1950, Oct. (Box 3)
      - 1950, Nov.
      - 1950, Dec.
      - General 1950
      - 1951, Jan.
      - 1951, Feb.-Mar.
      - 1951, Apr.
      - 1951, May
      - 1951, June-Aug.
      - 1951, Sept.-Oct.
      - 1951, Sept.-Oct. (Box 1)
      - 1951, Nov. (Box 3)
      - 1951, Nov. (Box 1)
      - 1951, Dec. (Box 3)
      - 1951, Dec. (Box 1)
      - General 1951 (Box 3)
      - 1952, Jan.-Mar.
      - 1952, Apr.-June
      - 1952, July-Dec.
      - General 1952
      - 1953, Jan.-Sept.
      - 1953, Oct.-Dec.
      - General 1953
      - 1954, Jan.-June
      - 1954, July-Dec.
      - General 1954
      - 1955
      - 1956, Jan.-July
      - 1956, Aug.-Sept.
      - 1956, Oct.-Dec.
      - General 1956
      - 1957
      - 1958
      - 1959-1962
      - 1963-1968
      - General 1960s
      - 1980-1992
      - 1993-1994
      - 1995
      - 1995 (Box 3)
      - 1996-2006 (Box 3)
      - 1990s and 2000s (Box 4)
      - Anna Kris, 1951-1952, undated
    - Letters from Meier, ca. 1931-1969
      Most of the letters are written to her parents, Joseph Willen and Pearl Willen
      - ca. 1931-1943
      - 1943, ca. Jan.-June
      - 1943, ca. July-Dec.
      - 1944-1947
      - 1948
      - ca. 1931-1948
      - 1949, Jan.-Oct.
      - 1949, Jan.-Oct. (Box 3)
      - 1949, Nov.-Dec. (Box 4)
      - 1950
      - 1951
      - ca. 1950-1951
      - 1952
      - 1953
      - 1954
      - 1955
      - ca. 1951-1955
      - 1956
      - 1957
      - ca. 1949-1959
      - 1958-1964
      - ca. 1960s
      - ca. 1970s
    - Letters between others, 1927-1967, undated
      - Letters to Fred Meier, 1952-1963
      - Letters to Paul Willen, ca. 1943-1956
      - Letters from Paul Willen, 1939-1951, undated
      - Letters to Pearl and Joseph Willen, 1927-1965, undated
      - Letters to Pearl and Joseph Willen, 1927-1965, undated (Box 3)
      - Letters from Pearl and Joseph Willen, 1934-1963, undated (Box 4)
      - Letters, writings, and drawings from Donald Larner to Pearl Willen and Sara Larner, 1946-1967, undated
      - Letters between Pearl and Joseph Willen, 1945-1956, undated
      - Miscellaneous, 1932-1954, undated
  - Professional, 1982-2009, undated (Box 4)
    - General
      Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent
      - A
        List of correspondents:
        Abu-Shamis, Alia, 1993
        Academic High School, Jersey City Public Schools, 1994
        Acosta, Louisa,
        Ackerman Institute for Family Therapy, 1983-1987
        Adams, Elizabeth, 1988
        Aeer, Charlotte C., 2004 (Includes enclosure)
        Ahuvi, Marjorie, 1994
        Albany High School, 1997
        Albuquerque Teachers Federation, 2004
        Allen, David, 1997
        Alternative Community School, 1988
        Alternative High School Programs, 1988
        Alvarez, Shadia, former CPESS student at Antioch College, 1993 (Includes enclosure)
        American Association for Higher Education, 1995
        American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1994
        American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1995
        American Educational Research Association, 2008
        American Federation of Teachers, 1999-2000
        Annenberg Institute for School Reform, 1998
        Annenberg, Lee, 1995
        Annenberg, Walter, 1995
        Armington, David, 1994-2000
        ArtsConnection, 1994
        Aspen Institute for Humanistic Studies, undated
        Association for Union Democracy, 1985
        Association of California School Administrators, 1995
        Association of Teacher Educators, 1997
        Association of the Bar of the City of New York, 1994
        Avery School, 2006
        Ayers, William, of the University of Illinois at Chicago, 1993-1994
      - B
        Bank Street College, 1994-1996
        Bard College, 1995
        Barrington Alternative School, 1989
        Bates College, 1994-2003
        Bay, Fred, 2004
        BBC Education, 1988
        Becker, Jerry, 2008
        Bell, Peter D., of the Edna McConnell Clark Foundation, 1987
        Benson, Dawn, 1998-1999, undated
        Bentley, James, former CPESS student at Brooklyn Law School, 1998
        Bigelow, Don, of the United States Department of Education, 1997
        Binswanger, Robert, of Dartmouth College, 1996
        Blumenthal, Amy, of Northeastern Illinois University's Chicago Teachers' Center, 1987
        Board of Cooperative Educational Services, 1987
        Bolitzer, Susan, 1991-1992
        Bougas, Jim, 2000
        Bracey, Gerald W., 1993-1995
        Bradley, Maggie, undated
        Brady, Connie, 1994-1998 (Includes enclosures.) (See also: Professional Activities; Central Park East; CPE I, II, and River East; Meeting notes, memos, and correspondence with staff; Oversize 3, folder 8)
        Brady, Marion, 1995 (Includes enclosures)
        Braunstein, Sumner, 1995
        Breving, Bob, 1995
        Brick, Lisa, 1996
        Brisben, Quinn, 1995
        Britannica Educational Corporation, 1989
        Brocato, Kay of Mississippi State University, 2005
        Brown, Dan, 2007
        Brion-Meisels, Steven, 1997
        Burke, Ellyn, 1995
        Burton, Jeanne, 1995
        Bush Principals' Leadership Program, 1988
        Butts, John K. of the Leadership Forum, 1995
        Byers, Happie, 1995, undated
      - C
        California Center for School Restructuring, 1996
        California Federation of Teachers, 1988
        Cambridge School, 1988
        Capitol Region Education Council, 1996
        CARE, 2000-2001
        Carmel Central School District, 1988 (Includes enclosures)
        Cartwright, Sally, 1999
        Castro, Lillian, undated
        Center for Educational Innovation, 1994-1995
        Center for Leadership in School Reform, 1994
        Center for National Policy, 1995
        Center for the Advancement of Group Studies, 1993
        Center for the Development of Teaching, 2000
        Center on Organization and Restructuring of Schools, 1993-1995
        Central Park East Secondary School, undated
        Chancellor Search Committee, 1988-1993 (Includes letters from Meier)
        Chappaqua Central School District, 1987
        Charles Hayden Foundation, 1987
        Char[?]ey, Ruth, 1997
        Chico, Gery, 2000 (Includes letter from Meier)
        Children's Aid Society, 1994
        Children's Defense Fund, 1987-1995
        City-as-School, 1988-1995
        City Club of New York, 1995
        City University of New York, 1989-1994
        Clark, Jack, 1996
        Clark University, 1987-1996
        Clements, Phyllis Harris, 1995
        Clinton, Bill, Governor of Arkansas and President of the United States, 1987-1993
        Coalition of Essential Schools, 1994-1995
        Cobblestone Publishing, 1994 (Includes letter from Meier)
        College of the Atlantic, 1993
        Columbia University College of Physicians and Surgeons, 1996
        Columbia University Graduate School of Business, 1995
        Columbia University Teachers College, 1987-1995
        Community Music Works Forum, 2004
        Community School, 1994
        Connie Clausen Associates, 1994
        Coro: A Foundation for Leadership, 1995
        Cotton, Hank, 1996
        Council of Urban Boards of Education, 2002
        Courtines, Etienne, former student, 1994-1996, undated (Separate folder)
        Cruz-Acosta, Louisa, 1995
        Cunningham, George, 2000
        Cuomo, Mario, Governor of New York, 1988 (Letter from Meier, includes response from Thomas A. Coughlin III of the New York Department of Correctional Services)
      - D
        D'Amore, L. Simone, of Antioch University, 1996
        Darling-Hammond, Linda, 1994 (Letter from Meier)
        David, Jane L. of the Bay Area Research Group, 1996
        Davidson, Florence H., 1994 (Includes enclosure)
        Davidson, Joan, 1993
        Davidson, Miriam, 1991-1995 (Includes letters from Meier, enclosures)
        Dawson, Priscilla, 2008
        Delavan, Garrett, undated
        Delforge, Beth, 1998
        Democratic Socialists of America, 1994
        Diamond, Irene of the Aaron Diamond Foundation, 1996
        Dispenza, Mary C., 1996 (Includes enclosures)
        Dissent, 1988-2002
        Dowling, Maureen, 1996-1997 (Includes enclosures)
        Downey, Thomas J., Representative of New York, Congress of the United States, 1983-1988
        Dream Keepers, 1996
        Duckworth, Eleanor, 1992-1997
      - E
        Economic Policy Institute, 2008
        Education Week, 1994
        Education Writers Association, 1994
        Educational Equity Concepts, 1994
        Educational Leadership, 1993-2003
        Educational Policy, 1991
        Einstein High School, 1988
        Elwood Union Free School District, 1987
        Engaged Learner Conference, 2008